marketsurveys.com 2008-12-17

# Privacy Statement from Market Surveys

** Recent Survey  
A Stressed-Out Society **

Market Surveys ("MS") is a survey research company and our use of your information is strictly limited in accordance with this Privacy Policy. To use MarketSurveys.com and its related sister sites (including MarketSurveys.com, SurveyMojo.com, YourInterestsOnly.com, ExpressMyOpinions.com, MusicSurveys.com, MovieSurveys.com, EmployeeSatisfaction.com, SatisfactionSurveys.com, RestaurantSurveys.com, QueEncuestas.com, and EncuestasdeOpiniones.com (collectively, the "MS Sites") you must register as a User (at no charge) and be at least thirteen (13) years old. The MS Sites neither target, nor are intended for, children. 

## Information Market Surveys collects

The information we collect helps us ensure that our services are best designed to meet your needs. MS receives and stores information that you enter when you register on the MS Sites and on MS Site forms. Typically, these are registration forms to take and/or create surveys, contests, or other promotions. Because participation on MS Sites is strictly voluntary, you are free to decide whether or not you wish to participate in any given survey, contest, or other promotion, and you can choose whether or not to disclose the requested information. If some information is required and some is optional, we will make this distinction clear. We collect both contact and other types of information: 

**(i)** your survey responses concerning products, services or other subjects covered in that survey ("Survey Data"); 

**(ii)** your demographic profile, such as gender, age, income, geographic area, or other characteristics ("Demographic Data"); 

**(iii)** your personally identifiable information (including email address) and other identifying information that you choose to provide, such as your physical address, first and last name, phone number, or other contact information ("PII"); and 

**(iv)** your IP address, with a "cookie", which is a piece of data stored on your hard drive containing information about you. We collect this to analyze trends, administer the site, track Users' movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. You can set your browser to not accept cookies, but please note that by doing so certain features of MS may not work. See your browser's documentation for more information on accepting cookies. Our use of cookies and tracking of IP addresses are not linked to PII. 

When you create an account we will send you a confirmation e-mail acknowledging your new account to the address that was supplied us. This e-mail will give you the option to delete your account, in case you change your mind or in case you are not the one who registered your email address with MS. Please keep the confirmation e-mail, as it also contains helpful contact information. 

## How we use User information

Survey Data and Demographic Data are tabulated collectively using data from all respondents, and are provided to research clients only in aggregate statistical form. We do not provide research clients with your PII. 

MS does not send unsolicited or "spam" e-mail. We send e-mails to registered Users and others who have given us permission to communicate alerts about new surveys, as well as send newsletters and or other pertinent information, including special offers and new products that may be of interest. Additionally, we occasionally send email offers on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we do not share any of your PII with these businesses. 

Please note that we have entered into business relationships with third parties that make available prizes, sweepstakes, and other offers to our panelists that, if accepted by a panelist, require us to share PII with the third party providing the offer. The IP address of any panelist accepting such offers, as well as date and time of acceptance, may also be shared with the third parties associated with their offers. 

Further, as part of the registration process, we offer you the option to take advantage of one or more offers from our partners. Unless explicitly stated otherwise, all offers are optional and you do not have to signup for any offers in order to participate in the main promotional offer (although you may need to uncheck certain boxes to do so). If you do signup for an offer, we will share information about you only with those selected partners from whom you have chosen to receive information. All offers have Terms and Conditions links that we encourage you to read. We may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf (e.g., fulfilling orders). They have access to PII to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. 

We send to your web browser many of the advertisements you see when you use the MS Sites. We also allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within our web pages. Because your web browser must request these advertising banners from the ad network Web site, these companies can send their own cookies to your cookie file, just as if you had requested a web page from the site. Please note that if an advertiser asks us to show an advertisement to a certain audience (for example, men ages 18-34) or audience segment (for example, men ages 13-24 who have viewed sports content) and you respond to that ad, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. We only authorize the third-party ad servers to employ anonymous cookies for ad delivery and anonymous targeting; they should not collect, nor do we give them access to, any PII. If you want to prevent a third-party ad server from sending and reading cookies on your computer, currently you must visit each ad network's Web site individually and opt out (if they offer this capability). 

MS has also entered into partnerships with other online third party market research companies for MS to send their survey invitations to you that take you to their online surveys and they may provide their own incentives for participation. For example, MS has entered into such an agreement with Global Market Insite (GMI) of Seattle, Washington, which pays cash to respondents in exchange for taking surveys as part of its survey panel, GlobalTestMarket. Please see GMI's [privacy policy](http://www.globaltestmarket.com/privacypolicy.php) and [user agreement](http://www.globaltestmarket.com/useragreement.php) for details. MS panelists are not obligated to participate in GMI surveys, but they may if they wish. You may opt out of GMI's panel at any time without affecting your status as a MS panelist; likewise, you may opt out of MS without affecting your status as a GMI panelist. 

This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this and all MS Sites. We work to protect your information by using Secure Socket Layers (SSL) software to encrypt your information when it is being transmitted to us, and access to data is limited through the use of internal firewalls and strictly enforced. It is against our policy to provide any customer information to any third party except as stated in this Privacy Policy. While we strive to protect your PII, MS cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Although we strongly encourage all of our partners to post their privacy policies on their sites and to adhere to the same high security standards as we do, we cannot ensure or warrant their information policies or security measures. Thus, we disclaim any responsibility for the actions of these third parties. 

## Public Forums and Comments

The MS Sites may make forums, user-created surveys, and message boards available to its Users. MS does not collect any User data through such forums, surveys, and message boards. Nonetheless, please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose PII online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that such information can be collected and used by others. Such third party conduct is not within the control of MS. As a result, you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your PII in these forums. 

All feedback or comments submitted to us are the property of MS and we may use this information for our own marketing purposes or to contact you for further feedback on the site. 

## Disclosure of User Information

We may release User or account information as necessary (1) to our partners as set forth above; (2) to comply with the law; (3) to enforce or apply our Rules or Disclaimers; or (4) to protect the rights, property, or safety of MS, its subsidiaries, affiliates or partners, our Users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection. 

Of course, at some time in the future a third party could acquire the MS business or assets of the business in order to conduct their own surveys with panel members. If the MS business, the panel, or a part of the panel is acquired by such a third party, Personally Identifiable Information would be transferred to the acquiror. 

## How can I change my information?

If you'd like to change your account information, please visit the Member's Area of MarketSurveys.com, enter your email address and password and click "Sign In". You will then have access to change your Personally Identifiable Information. If you would like to leave the MS panel completely, send us an email via the "Contact Us" link with the word "unsubscribe" in the subject box. Or, you can unsubscribe from the MS panel by responding to an email we have sent to you with "unsubscribe" in your email response. If you opt not to receive e-mail from us we will honor your request and not send e-mail unless we need to notify you that you are a contest winner. Please note that if you have submitted PII under more than one e-mail address, you must unsubscribe from each address separately. MS will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete records from our mailing list when we receive requests to do so. Because of possible retention of a residual copy in a system backup file, however, we cannot guarantee deletion in every instance. 

## Effective Date of Privacy Policy

MS reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at its sole discretion at any time. If it does so, MS will inform panelists of any such change by posting it on the MS Sites. The effective date of any change of privacy policy will be clearly marked. This Privacy Policy is effective as of March 01, 2007. 

Click here to unsubscribe
